Curt Stern Papers 1907-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.5
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 1907-1981 (Box 1-43)
  - Mampell, Klaus, 1951-1966; 8 items (Box 16)
  - Manfred, Ernest F., 1957; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Mangelsdorf, A.J., 1929-1972; 3 items (Box 16)
  - Mangelsdorf, Paul C., 1963-1968; 11 items (Box 16)
  - Manojlovic, Nikolaus, 1966-1968; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Manwell, Clyde, 1968; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Marchetti, Andrew A., 1966-1967; 4 items (Box 16)
  - Margolin, Sydney G., 1967; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Marine Biological Laboratory (Woods Hole, Mass.), 1935; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Markert, Clement L., 1970; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Marler, Peter, 1964-1966; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Maroni, Gustavo P., 1972; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Martell, Edward A., 1975; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Maruyama, Magoroh, 1964-1971; 4 items (Box 16)
  - Massie, F. Stanford, 1965; 3 items (Box 16)
  - Masui, Kiyoshi, 1929-1967; 3 items (Box 16)
  - Mather, Kenneth, 1946; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Mathew, P.M., 1968; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Mathur, Jaswant Raj, 1970; 3 items (Box 16)
  - Matson, Wallace I., 1967; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Matsumura, S., 1931; 1 item (Box 16)
  - Matsunaga, E., 1965-1968; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Matthaus, William, 1953; 5 items (Box 16)
  - Maxwell, Dillar, 1966-1968; 5 items (Box 16)
  - May, Sterling R., 1967; 2 items (Box 16)
  - Mayr, Ernst, 1943-1974; 4 folders (Box 16)
    Baur, Erwin; Biographical and personal data; Charles, Donald Randolph; Committee activities -- Common Problems of Genetics and Paleontology; Conferences and symposia -- Princeton Conference; Congratulations, greetings, thanks -- National Medal of Science; Embryology, developmental genetics; Evolution; Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict; History of biology, especially genetics; Levine, Paul; Population genetics; Publication; Recommendations -- Crow, James F.; Recommendations -- Lewontin, Richard Charles; Referee's report -- Caspari, Ernst Wilhelm; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Society for the Study of Evolution; Timofeeff-Ressovsky, Nikolai W.; Verschuer, Otmar, Freiherr von; Weismann, August; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1943-1944; 15 items (Box 16)
    - Folder 2, 1946-1947; 6 items (Box 16)
    - Folder 3, 1954-1971; 17 items (Box 16)
    - Folder 4, 1974; 8 items (Box 16)
  - Mechelke, F., 1961; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Medawar, Peter B., 1961-1966; 4 items (Box 17)
  - Medawar, Peter B. "The Future of Man", n.d.; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Medical Research Council, 1967; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Medina, Arturo Valls, 1954; 6 items (Box 17)
  - Medvedev, N.N., 1930; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Medvedev, Zh. A., 1962-1971; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Meehl, Paul E., 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Melchers, Georg, 1968-1973; 5 items (Box 17)
  - Mellen, Sydney, 1975; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Memorabilia and Miscellany, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 14 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 13 items (Box 17)
  - Mendelsohn, Everett, 1967; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Menesini, Mario M., 1966; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Mertens, Thomas R., 1966; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Messinger, Harley B., 1964; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., 1968; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Mettler, Lawrence E., 1970; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Metz, Charles W., 1928-1941; 12 items (Box 17)
  - Mezie, Daniel, 1950; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Michaeles, L., 1938; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Michener, Charles D., 1964; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Microinjection supplies, n.d.; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Middletown Scientific Assoc., 1944; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Mikhailoff, Serge, 1960; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Milch, Robert Austin, 1965; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Miles, Winifred C., 1966; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Milkman, Roger, 1961; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Miller, Albert, 1940; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Miller, Orlando, 1965-1966; 4 items (Box 17)
  - Mills, Charles. "Chromosome Anomalies and Related Conditions", 1960; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Millward, David K., 1969; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Minerva (Journal), 1975; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Minkler, Donald, 1966; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Minnich, Dwight E., 1946-1947; 9 items (Box 17)
  - Miramonte High School (Acalanes Union High School District, Ca.), 1959-1969; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Mirsky, Alfred E., 1969; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Mislin, H., 1959; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Mitsuda, Hisatoshi, 1967-1968; 5 items (Box 17)
  - Mittwoch, Ursula, 1966; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Moberg, Guillermina Hinojora de, 1967; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1944-1945; 5 items (Box 17)
  - Moewus, Franz, 1948; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Moffitt, Francis H., 1974; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Mohan, Jag, 1970; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Mohler, Dawson, 1957-1966; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Mohr, Otto Lous, 1926-1960; 2 folders (Box 17)
    Bauer, Hans; Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Brasted, Adair; Displaced German scholars; Drosophila genetics; Genetics; Ibsen; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Mossige, Jeanne Coyne; Muller, Hermann Joseph; Munch, E.; Nachtsheim, Hans; Political issues; Teaching -- University of Oslo; Timofeeff-Ressovsky, Nikolai W.; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Norway
    - Folder 1, 1926-1932; 38 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 2, 1933-1960; 8 items (Box 17)
  - Mohr, Otto L. "Genetics Institute, Oslo, Norway" [1945?], n.d.; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Mohr, Tove (Box 17)
  - Monie, I.W., 1965; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Montagu, M.F. Ashley, 1949-1950; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Montalenti, G., 1945-1970; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Moore, John A., 1945-1967; 4 items (Box 17)
  - Moore, Thomas, 1947; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Morehouse College. Distinguished Visiting Professors Program, 1967-1968; 3 items (Box 17)
  - Morey, Martha B., 1948-1975; 4 items (Box 17)
  - Morgan, Thomas Hunt, 1927-1941; 2 folders (Box 17)
    Belar, Karl; Bernstein, Felix; Biographical and personal data; California Institute of Technology; Congratulations, greetings, thanks -- 75th birthday; Drosophila genetics; Fellowships, assistantships; Hogben, Lancelot; Laboratory techniques, equipment; University of Rochester
    - Folder 1, 1927-1929; 7 items (Box 17)
    - Folder 2, 1932-1941; 14 items (Box 17)
  - Morgan, Mrs. T. H. (Lilian V.), 1946-1952; 11 items (Box 17)
  - Moritz, Karl, 1969; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Moriwaki, Daigoro, 1958-1969; 7 items (Box 17)
  - Morrison, A. Cressy, 1944; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Morse, Wayne, 1966; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Morton, Newton E., 1971; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Morton, N. E. "Population genetics and disease control", 1970; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Moscona, A.A., 1964; 2 items (Box 17)
  - Moseley, Helen Rydquest. "... Crossing over at the Bar Region of Drosophila Melanogaster" Thesis, 1943, 3 folders (Box 17)
    Drosophila genetics -- Crossing over; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1943; 1 item (Box 17)
    - Folder 2, 1943; 1 item (Box 17)
    - Folder 3, 1943; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Mota, Miguel, 1957; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Mothes, Kurt, 1964-1966; 6 items (Box 18)
  - Motulsky, Arno G., 1967-1971; 5 items (Box 18)
  - Motz, Gunther, 1972; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Mt. Diablo Council for the United Nations, 1955; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Mukherjee, A. S. (Ardendu S.), 1958-1972; 2 folders (Box 18)
    Biographical and personal data; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Editorial matters; Fellowships, assistantships; Graduate study; Human genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Muller, Hermann Joseph; Tokunaga, Chiyoko
    - Folder 1, 1958-1968; 29 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 2, 1969-1972; 18 items (Box 18)
  - Mukherjee, Barid B., 1975; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Muller, Hermann J., 1926-1967; 12 folders (Box 18)
    Agol, I. J.; Amherst College; Bacterial genetics; Biographical and personal data; Cytogenetics; Delbruck, Max; Drosophila genetics; Ephrussi, Boris; Fellowships, assistantships; Genetics -- Mutation rates; Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict; Indiana University; Levit, Solomon G.; Offerman, Carlos; Painter, Theophilus Shickel; Plough, Harold Henry; Political issues -- U.S.S.R.; Publication; Radiation genetics; Research support; Reviews; Russian politics and science; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Spencer, Warren P.; Sutton, Eileen; Teaching; University of Rochester; University of Texas; Wilson, Edwin Bidwell; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1926-1929; 13 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 2, 1930; 9 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 3, 1931-1933; 16 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 4, 1940-1943; 18 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 5, 1944; 27 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 6, 1945; 7 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 7, 1946; 22 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 8, 1947; 18 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 9, 1948-1949; 8 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 10, 1950-1953; 16 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 11, 1955-1961; 13 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 12, 1962-1967; 22 items (Box 18)
  - Muller, H. J. "The Gene" 1945, 1947; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Muller, H. J. "The Gene as the Basis of Life" 1924, 1929; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Muller, H. J., et al. "Genetic effects of radiation on man", 1956; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Muller, Mrs. Hermann J., 1967-1972; 6 items (Box 18)
  - Mulvihill, John J., 1970; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Muntzing, Arve, 1934-1947; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Murlin, John R., 1942; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Murphy, Collin, 1967-1972; 5 items (Box 18)
  - Murphy, Edmond A. "Probability", 1970; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Murphy, Robert, 1965; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Mutation Research (Journal), 1971; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Nabours, Robert Kirkland, 1930; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Nachtsheim, Hans, 1927-1967; 6 items (Box 18)
    Bacterial genetics; Biographical and personal data; Butenandt, Adolph Friedrich Johann; Correns, Carl; Genetics -- Mammals; Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict; Gruneberg, Hans; Human genetics; Kaudewitz, Fritz; Max-Planck Institutes; Mendel, Gregor; Political issues; Seiler, Jakob; Timofeeff-Ressovsky, Nikolai W.; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Tschermak-Seysenegg, Erich von; Vogel, Friedrich; Warburg, Otto
  - Nadkarni, M. G., 1966; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Nagarajan, A., 1950-1951; 4 items (Box 18)
  - Nance, Walter E., 1964; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Nandi, Satyabrata, 1971; 2 items (Box 18)
  - Nanney, David L., 1954; 3 items (Box 18)
  - Nast, Manfred, 1965; 1 item (Box 18)
  - Nathan, Henry, 1968; 2 items (Box 18)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1948-1978; 2 folders (Box 18)
    Bibliographical matters -- Nominees; Biographical and personal data -- Neel, James V.; Biographical and personal data -- Pincus, Gregory; Congratulations, greetings, thanks -- Kimber Award; Dunn, Leslie Clarence; Educational matters; Muller, Hermann Joseph; National Academy of Sciences; National Research Council; Political issues
    - Folder 1, 1974; 6 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 2, 1948-1978; 33 items (Box 18)
  - National Academy of Sciences. Proceedings, 1971-1973; 5 items (Box 18)
  - National Association of Biology Teachers, 1974; 1 item (Box 18)
  - National Center for Atmospheric Research, 1974-1975; 2 items (Box 18)
  - National Committee for J. F. Kennedy, 1960; 1 item (Box 18)
  - National Committee on Radiation Protection and Measurements, 1963-1964; 2 folders (Box 18)
    Committee activities; Political issues; Radiation genetics
    - Folder 1, 1963; 1 item (Box 18)
    - Folder 2, 1964; 2 items (Box 18)
  - National Council on Radiation Protection and Measurements, 1966-1967; 4 folders (Box 18)
    Business; National Council on Radiation Protection; Political issues; Radiation genetics; Research support
    - Folder 1, 1967; 2 items (Box 18)
    - Folder 2, 1967; 1 item (Box 18)
    - Folder 3, 1966-1967; 1 item (Box 18)
    - Folder 4, 1967; 5 items (Box 18)
  - The National Foundation, 1972-1973; 8 items (Box 18)
  - National Research Council, 1947; 3 items (Box 18)
    Lewis Weed
  - National Roster of Scientific Personnel (Box 19)
    see Carmichael, L.
  - National Science Foundation. Application for grant, 1961; 1 item (Box 19)
  - National Science Teachers Association, 1966; 2 items (Box 19)
  - National Science Teachers Association. Vistas of Science, 1964; 3 items (Box 19)
  - National Union of South African Students, 1956-1957; 3 items (Box 19)
  - Naturwissenschaften (Journal), 1932; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Naville, Andrë, 1953; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Nawar, Maher M., 1966; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Nebel, Bernard R., 1941-1945; 5 items (Box 19)
  - Nebel, Mabel R., 1963; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Neel, James V., 1939-1982; 7 folders (Box 19)
    American Institute of Biological Sciences; American Philosophical Society; Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission -- Japan; Atomic Energy Commission; Beadle, George Wells; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Dartmouth College; Drosophila genetics; Editorial matters; Embryology, developmental genetics; Fellowships, assistantships; Graduate study; Human genetics; International Congress of Genetics -- Seventh Congress; National Academy of Sciences; Publication; Radiation genetics; Recommendations -- Neel, James V.; Shull, George Harrison; Teaching; University of Rochester; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1939; 10 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 2, 1940-1941; 20 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 3, 1941; 11 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 4, 1942-1947; 15 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 5, 1951-1954; 7 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 6, 1856-1957; 9 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 7, 1959-1982; 30 items (Box 19)
  - Neeley, John C., 1966; 2 items (Box 19)
  - Nei, Masatoshi, 1971; 2 items (Box 19)
  - Nemeth, L., 1928; 2 items (Box 19)
  - Nesbitt, Muriel N., 1971; 3 items (Box 19)
  - Neuburger, Arthur, 1964; 2 items (Box 19)
  - New England Institute, 1966-1967; 4 items (Box 19)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1968; 2 items (Box 19)
  - Newman, H.H., 1942; 3 items (Box 19)
  - Newman, James R., 1960; 2 items (Box 19)
  - News Clippings, 1937-1964; 35 items (Box 19)
  - Neyman, J., 1974; 4 items (Box 19)
  - Ngo, Lim Siew, 1966; 4 items (Box 19)
  - Nicholas, J.S., 1947; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Niel, C. B. van (Box 19)
    see Van Niel
  - Nilan, Robert A., 1965-1968; 4 items (Box 19)
  - Ninnis, Judy C., 1966; 2 items (Box 19)
  - Nishimura, Hideo, 1959; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Nixon, Richard M. (Pres. U.S.) "Science and Technology." Address to Congress, March 16, 1972, 2 items (Box 19)
  - Noble, Charles A., 1960; 2 items (Box 19)
  - Nöthiger, Rolf, 1965-1971; 24 items (Box 19)
  - Novales, Ronald R., 1968; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Novitski, Edward, 1940-1979; 5 folders (Box 19)
    Becker, Hans Joachim; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Editorial matters; Fellowships, assistantships; History of biology, especially genetics -- Morgan, Thomas Hunt; Human genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Lerner, Isadore Michael; Lewis, Edward B.; Mampell, Klaus; Publication; Radiation genetics; Recommendations -- Hovanitz, William; Recommendations -- Mazia, Daniel; Reviews; Teaching -- Green, Melvin Martin; Teaching -- Griffen, Allen B.; Teaching -- Stadler, Lewis John; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; University of California, Berkeley; University of Missouri; University of Rochester
    - Folder 1, 1940-1948; 21 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 2, 1950-1954; 4 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 3, 1958-1964; 21 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 4, 1965-1975; 22 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 5, 1978-1979; 4 items (Box 19)
  - Nusbaum, Mrs. Jesse L., 1957; 2 items (Box 19)
  - Nyhan, William L., 1967; 2 items (Box 19)
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory. Advisory Committee for Biology, 1955-1968; 5 folders (Box 19)
    Atomic Energy Commission; Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Committee activities -- Advisory Committee for Biology; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Hollaender, Alexander; Human genetics; Mouse genetics; Oak Ridge National Laboratory; Political issues; Radiation genetics; Russell, William Lawson; Teaching
    - Folder 1, 1967; 2 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 2, 1955; 4 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 3, 1955; 9 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 4, 1962-1965; 3 items (Box 19)
    - Folder 5, 1967-1968; 3 items (Box 19)
  - Oakberg, E.F., 1957-1958; 2 items (Box 19)
  - Oakley, Kenneth P., 1967; 3 items (Box 19)
  - Obstetrical and Gynecological Assembly of Southern California, 1956-1957; 7 items (Box 19)
  - Ode an den Stern (poem; in German), 1 item (Box 19)
  - Oehlkers, Friedrich, 1951-1972; 3 items (Box 19)
  - Oftedal, Per, 1968; 2 items (Box 19)
  - Oguma, Kan, 1950; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Ogura, S., 1930; 3 items (Box 19)
  - Ohkura, Koji, 1956-1969; 15 items (Box 19)
  - Ohno, Susumu, 1964-1967; 4 items (Box 19)
  - Oksala, Tarvo, 1961; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Olby, Robert C., 1968-1970; 10 items (Box 20)
  - Oliver, Clarence P., 1931-1947; 4 items (Box 20)
  - Oltmanns, -----, 1931; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Omenn, Gilbert S., 1973; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Ontario Deptartment of Education. Educational Television Branch, 1968; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Opitz, John M., 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Oppenheimer, Jane, 1970-1975; 5 items (Box 20)
  - Orel, V. (Vitezslav), 1966-1975; 28 items (Box 20)
    Bibliographical matters; Conferences and symposia -- Mendel Symposium, Brno; History of biology, especially genetics -- Mendel, Gregor; Honors; Human genetics; Olby, Robert Cecil
  - Ortiz, Eugenio, 1958-1972; 13 items (Box 20)
  - Osborn, Frederick, 1954-1968; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Osborn, Frederick. The Future of Human Heredity (Stern's comments), 1968; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Oshima, Chozo, 1968; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Owen, D.F., 1964; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Owen, Raymond D., 1958-1971; 7 items (Box 20)
  - Owen, Ray D. "Immunogenetics", 1958; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Oxford University Press, 1964; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Padgett, Jeff. "Genes and People" (poem), 1976; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Pagano, J. E. (letter to R. Goldschmidt), 1955; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Page, Ernest W., 1957-1967; 6 items (Box 20)
  - Page, Irvine H., 1964; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Paik, Yong Kyun, 1958; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Painter, John, 1971; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Painter, Theophilus S., 1934-1969; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Papazian, Haig P., 1962; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Papenfuss, George F., 1958; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Papp, Eugene, 1955; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Parisi, Paolo, 1972-1974; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Park, In-Joo, 1970; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Parker, Dean R., 1968; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Parker, G.H., 1940; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Parry, William L., 1964; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Parson, William, 1955; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Parsons, James J., 1966-1971; 7 items (Box 20)
  - Parsons, Talcott, 1972-1974; 6 items (Box 20)
  - Pascher, A., 1928; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Passarge, Eberhard, 1967; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Pasteur, Georges, 1970; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Patau, Klaus, 1960-1975; 4 items (Box 20)
  - Pathak, Chandravadan H., 1954; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Patterson, J. T. (John Thomas), 1933-1945; 27 items (Box 20)
    Cytogenetics; Displaced German Scholars -- Gruneberg, Hans; Drosophila genetics; Fellowships, assistantships; Human genetics; MacKnight, Robert H.; Population genetics; Recommendations -- Burdette, Walter; Stone, Wilson Stuart
  - Pauling, Linus, 1957-1962; 7 items (Box 20)
  - Paulson, Richard E., 1964; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Payne, Fernandus, 1948; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Pearson, Helen M., 1966-1975; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Pearson, P., 1964; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Pearson, Theodore I., 1966; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Pease, Mrs. Donald, 1968; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Pease, Michael S., 1929-1931; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Pellew, Caroline, 1928-1930; 17 items (Box 20)
  - Penrose, Lionel S., 1941-1990 (ca); 7 items (Box 20)
  - Penrose, Mrs. Lionel S., 1956-1972; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Peppler, Wayne L., 1968; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Perkins, David, 1948-1959; 5 items (Box 20)
  - Perkins, Dexter, 1943; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Perspectives in Biology and Medicine (Journal), 1966-1968; 19 items (Box 20)
  - Peruvian Society of Medical Genetics, 1972; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Peterfi, T. (?), 1946; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Peterson, Peter A., 1966; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Petrakis, Nicholas L., 1968; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Petrunkevitch, Alexander, 1945-1963; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Pfeiffer, Rudolf A., 1964; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1971; 5 items (Box 20)
  - Philip, Ursula, 1947-1973; 7 items (Box 20)
  - Philips, Fred S., n.d.; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Philiptschenko, Yuri [Filipchenko], 1929; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Phillips, Ross, 1940; 3 items (Box 20)
  - PHP Institute, 1970; 4 items (Box 20)
  - Physiographical Society of Lund, 1970; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Picken, Laurence, 1960; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Pieter, H., 1942; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Pilgrim, H. Ira, 1967; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Pilgrim, H. Ira and Charles Ludwig. "Acrocephalosyndactyly and other similar congenital anomalies", 1952; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Pipkin, Sarah Bedichek, 1953-1962; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Piternick, George, 1956-1966; 6 items (Box 20)
  - Piternick, Leonie, 1965-1970; 11 items (Box 20)
  - Planned Parenthood / World Population, 1966; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Plato, Chris C., 1957; 9 items (Box 21)
  - Poems, 1960; 12 items (Box 21)
  - Pogul, Stanley, 1947; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Pohley, Heinz Joachim, 1956; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Polani, Paul E., 1959-1972; 6 items (Box 21)
  - Polanyi, George, 1956; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Poll, Heinrich, 1927; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Pollister, Arthur W., 1939-1945; 5 items (Box 21)
  - Pollitzer, William S., 1966; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Popoff, Meth, 1928-1938; 3 items (Box 21)
  - Post, Richard Howell, 1957-1966; 7 items (Box 21)
  - Postcards (24 cards, ca. 1928-1931), 1928-1940 (ca); 24 items (Box 21)
  - Pradhan, Kanti Knmar, 1967; 3 items (Box 21)
  - Prakash, Satya, 1971; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Pratt, Edmund A., 1955; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Preer, J. R., 1948; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1964; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Prevosti, A., 1968; 3 items (Box 21)
  - Price, Bronson, 1950; 3 items (Box 21)
  - Price, George R., 1971; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Principles of Human Genetics, 1942-1983; 5 boxes (Box 21-25)
    Bibliographical matters; Business; Genetics; Human genetics; Publication -- Principles of Human Genetics; Reviews; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Figures #1, 1961-1969; 8 items (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Figures #2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Figures #3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Figures #4, n.d.; 1 item (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Preface, n.d.; 1 item (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 1, 1962-1968; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Folder 1, 1962; 1 item (Box 21)
      - Folder 2, 1964-1968; 1 item (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 2, 1962-1966; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Folder 1, 1962-1964; 1 item (Box 21)
      - Folder 2, 1966; 1 item (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 3, 1967-1969; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Folder 1, 1967-1968; 1 item (Box 21)
      - Folder 2, 1969; 1 item (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 4, 1966; 1 item (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 5, 1965; 1 item (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 6, 1969; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Folder 1, 1969; 1 item (Box 21)
      - Folder 2, 1969; 1 item (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 7, 1963-1972; 5 folders (Box 21)
      - Folder 1, 1963-1968; 7 items (Box 21)
      - Folder 2, 1965; 3 items (Box 21)
      - Folder 3, 1967-1969; 5 items (Box 21)
      - Folder 4, 1968-1971; 8 items (Box 21)
      - Folder 5, 1968-1972; 4 items (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 8, 1961-1966; 4 items (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 9, 1961-1972; 4 items (Box 21)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 10, 1970; 11 items (Box 22)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 11, 1962-1970; 5 items (Box 22)
    - Principles of Human Genetics - Chapter 12, 1970; 2 items (Box 22)